《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
欢迎回家，老大
Welcome home, boss.
-妈咪在哪里？ -妈咪等一下再来找我们
- Where's Mommy? - Mommy's gonna meet us later, okay?
-我不是杀人犯 -戴伦斯史泰门
- I'm not a murderer. - Terrence steadman.
-总统的胞弟 -我没有杀他
- The president's brother. - I didn't do it.
-史泰门先生，这是违禁品 -我带着防身用的
- Mr. Steadman, it's contraband. - I brought it to protect myself.
那是我们的职责
That's what we're here for.
食物的钱可以开支票吗？ 我没有K
Can I write a check? Because I don't have...
你好，贺兰德太太
Hello, Mrs. Hollander.
泰迪回家了
Teddy's home.
我是潘 怎么回事？
It's Pam. What's going on?
我爱你 帮我亲一下小卡好吗？
I love you.
Give Cam a kiss for me, okay?
你再打这支电话 你就死定了
You call this number again, you're a dead man.
你要我帮忙，比尔 而我要恢复职务
You want my help. I want my job back.
-你有何计划？ -等那两兄弟上了车
- What's your plan? - When brothers get in the van,
他们就只能等死
It's the last thing they'll do.
保罗凯勒曼在阿布奎基外 已布下人马，准备攻击车队
Paul Kellerman is ready to move on the caravan outside of Albuquerque.
到时一定会枪林弹雨
When it goes down, there's to be lots of bullets flying,
我要你确保 保罗凯勒曼中弹身亡
I need you there to make sure Paul Kellerman catches one.
雷诺兹总统毁了你们的人生
President Reynolds ruined your life...
也毁掉我的人生 如果你们想搞垮这贱人
...she ruined my life. You wanna take the bitch down...
我就是最佳内线 但现在是唯一的机会
...you found your inside man. But it's gotta be right now.
快走！
Let's go.
我有办法逃出去！
I know the way out.
派一组人马从西边包抄
I want a team flanking the west.
另一组人马到河边
Give me another team down by the river.
人员受伤 立刻派医务员来
Man down. Give me a Medivac, AsAP.
塔葛警官
Officer Tuggle.
塔葛警官？
Officer Tuggle?
我要找亚历山大曼宏 我是他的直属上司
I'm looking for Alexander Mahone. I'm his direct supervisor.
长官，我很遗憾 你的手下中弹了
I'm sorry to tell you this, sir, but your boy's been shot.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我曾是总统的手下
I used to work for the president.
你为何帮助我们？
Why are you helping us?
趴下去，快点！
Lay down on the floor. Now.
联邦探员，让我通过
Federal agent. Let me through.
空中小队说你的车子 沿着四十六号公路前进
Air support is telling us that they saw your vehicle traveling down Route 46.
逃犯可能会从四十六号公路逃走 我负责搜查
Forty-six is a possible exit route for the convicts. I was securing it.
长官，请别介意 我们要检查每一辆车
No offense, sir, but we're searching every vehicle.
别介意，让我通过 不然就请你的长官来
No offense. Either you let me through or you get me a supervisor.
这路障由我指挥 凯勒曼探员
I'm supervising this roadblock, Agent Kellerman.
抱歉，请你下车
I'm sorry, but I need you to get out of the vehicle.
汉费瑞斯K小队长
Sergeant Humphries.
这两个逃犯脱逃 还不到十分钟
Burrows and scofield have been loose for less than10 minutes.
代表目前每一秒都很重要 如果你再拖延我K
That means every second is critical. So if you detain me...
一秒钟 我会让你们全部被炒
...for one moment more, I will have all of your jobs.
听懂了吗？
Do you understand me?
-你走吧 -什么？
- Go ahead. - What?
让他走
Just let him go.
你还是没回答我的问题
You still haven't answered my question.
我为何帮助你们？
Why am I helping you?
因为敌人之敌就是朋友
Because the enemy of my enemy is my friend.
你提到搞垮总统 想必你已经有计划了
You said something about taking down the president. I assume you have a plan.
的确
I do.
我以前养过一只大丹狗 必须让他安乐死
I used to have a Great Dane. We had to put her down.
他走得很平静
It was very peaceful.
一下子就死了
One minute she was breathing, the next she wasn't.
转过去
Turn around.
起来！
Get up.
给我一个 不轰了你脑袋的好理由！
Give me one reason why I shouldn't blow your brains out.
因为我有让你自由的 唯一办法
Because I can give you the one thing that's gonna set you free.
我知道戴伦斯史泰门的下落
I know where Terrence steadman is.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：无名尸
你怎么知道史泰门的下落？
How do you know where steadman is?
因为一切都是我安排的
Because I arranged this whole thing.
-你安排陷害我？ -没错
- You arranged to set me up? - Right.
你安排杀害 所有我认识的人
You arranged the killing of all the people I know.
我只是听命行事
I was given orders. I executed those orders.
现在他们也要我的命 跟你们俩一样
And now I have a bull's-eye on my chest, just like you two.
-我不信任他 -等等
- I don't trust him. - Hey.
如果我要你死 你早就死了
If I wanted you dead, you'd be dead.
你们想继续逃亡，没关系
You guys want to keep running, fine.
如果想重获自由，就上车吧
You wanna be free, get in the car.
我不会邀请第二次
Last time I'm gonna offer.
（伊利诺州久利特 福克斯河监狱）
怎么啦，新来的？
What's up, fish?
看来你过得很不好
Looks like you're having a tough time of it.
-我没事 -我只是好奇
- I'm all right. - Well, I'm just curious.
你怎么不跟其他 也关在这里的前狱警混？
Why don't you hang out with the rest of the ex-guards who are locked up here?
对了
Oh, yeah.
这里一个也没有
There ain't any.
就只有你
It's just you.
等一下，等一下
Hey, hold. Hold up, hold up.
我心中有个互惠的点子
Now, I got what's called a mutual beneficial arrangement in my mind.
我会保护你 让别人不来找你麻烦
I'll look out after you. Make sure nobody get up in your mix.
你只需要把 下一餐的甜点给我
And all you got to do is bring me your dessert after the next meal.
就这么简单
It's real simple.
我只想服刑，不想惹麻烦
I'm just looking to do my time. I don't want any trouble.
好，你要的也是我要的
Yeah. It's what you want, and it's what I want.
下一餐的甜点
Your dessert after the next chow.
拿给我，懂了吗？
You bring it to me. You got it?
不，你找错人了
No. Wrong guy.
干嘛！
Hey.
分开！你们这些犯人！
Break it up, convicts.
没事的，老大
We're good, boss.
没事的
We're good.
把甜点拿给我K
You bring me my treat...
不然不会轻易放过你
...or this goes to the next level.
听懂了吗？
Do you understand?
他在问你问题，小子
He asked you a question, boy.
懂了
Yeah.
-我听不到，你呢？ -我也听不到
- I ain't hear him. You? - I ain't hear him.
好，我会的
Yeah. Okay.
你看，很简单吧？
See how easy that was?
现在起我们是好朋友了
We're gonna be good friends now.
（堪萨斯州，奈斯市）
There's no reason for you to be scared, suzie Q...
你没必要害怕，小苏珊K
因为我已经原谅你了
...because you see, I've forgiven you.
而你也可以原谅 我多年之前的不当之举
And you, in turn can forgive me for my indiscretions...
都过那么久了 现在回头看只是一些小@点
...which is far in the past they're nothing but specks in our respective rear views.
我们好久不见了
It's been such a long time.
你看起来真美
You look lovely.
好，我们现在就走 我们可以远走高飞
Okay, let's go. Right now. We can go away.
独处一阵子
Spend some time together.
苏珊，我不是玩具 所以请别玩弄我
Susan, I'm not a Victrola, so please don't play me like one.
你是绝对不可能K
There's not a white man's chance in Harlem...
丢下孩子不管的
...you'd ever leave your children behind.
对不起
I'm sorry.
别烦恼
Don't fret, now.
你来福克斯河监狱时K
When you came to Fox River...
你对我吐口水，仿佛我是K
...and you spat at me like I was some kind of...
丧心病狂的禽兽
...rabid animal.
其实我很开心
I was happy...
因为如此激烈的反应 只代表这女人还在乎你
...because such a visceral reaction could only come from a woman who still cares.
孩子们什么都不知道 我不想吓他们
The children don't know. I didn't wanna scare them...
所以你的事我没提过 求求你不要K
...so I never told them about you so please don't...
真是太完美了
That is so perfect.
你了解现在的情况吗？
Because you see what we got here now?
我们的过去 就跟白纸一样干净
We got ourselves a clean slate.
对吧？
Right?
原来阴谋就是这样 不是吗？
So, this is the conspiracy, huh?
一堆穿着西装的小鬼到处跑 互相残杀？
A bunch of little boys in suits running around trying to kill each other?
真是可悲
It's pathetic.
我们没想到 你们会那么难对付
Well, you were a little more formidable than we anticipated.
我们不需要你称赞，浑蛋
We don't need compliments out of you, jackass.
出现了
Oh, yes, there it is.
-柏劳讨人喜欢的个性 -闭嘴，开车
- The winning Burrows personality. - Shut your mouth and drive.
你真会讨陪审团的欢心 干得好
The one we really knew would win over a jury. Good work.
金先生
Mr. Kim.
到底出了什么事？
What the hell is going on out there?
刚刚一度有些混乱
It was touch and go for a minute,,,
但一切都在我的掌控中
...but I got everything handled.
曼宏中弹了
Mahone's been shot,
比尔，我知道，我在场 我看见柏劳开枪
Yes, I know, Bill, I was there. I saw Burrows pull the trigger.
-我们失去了宝贵的一员，但K -曼宏还活着
- We lost a valuable asset, but... - Mahone's alive.
很好，因为伤势看来不轻
That's good. It looked bad, so.
柏劳和斯科菲尔德在哪儿？
Where are Burrows and scofield?
这两兄弟已经死了
Burrows and scofield are dead.
尸体在我的车上 我现在正要去埋尸体
And they're in my sUV. I'm heading out to bury them. Right now.
不要埋尸体
Don't bury them.
我需要眼见为凭
I need visual confirmation.
我可以替你拍照
I'll get you a photo.
我再说一遍
I'll say it one more time.
-不要埋尸体 -你知道现在该说什么吗？
- Don't bury them. - You know what would be nice to hear?
道声谢
A thank you.
埋好尸体后我会回去报到
I'll report back when they're in the ground.
手机没关 会被追踪到
You leave that on, they'll trace it.
对，我是特勤局探员 无法追踪，但谢谢你关心
Yeah. Secret service. It's untraceable, but thanks.
（内布拉斯加州，蒙德市）
宝贝女儿
Hey, baby girl.
怎么了？
What?
怎么回事？
What's the matter?
-妈咪在哪里？ -别这样
- Where's Mommy? - Oh, come on.
我说过妈咪去帮朋友的忙
Now, I told you that Mommy was helping a friend.
好不好？ 我们很快就能见到她了
All right? Now, we're gonna see her real soon.
什么时候？
When?
宝贝，妈咪很快就会回来
Baby, we are gonna be with your mommy real soon.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
好吗？
Okay?
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
蒂蒂
Dede.
（北达柯塔州州立巡警）
Yo, Trey, It's me, man,
崔，是我
- What's up? - Yo, what's going on with Kacee?
-怎么了？ -凯西的情况如何？
我在法院 她很快就会被传讯
I'm at the courthouse. She's getting arraigned soon.
你和她谈过吗？ 她还好吧？
Okay. Well, you talk to her? Is she all right?
她在牢里，当然不好 他妈的到底怎么回事？
She's in jail, so, no, she's not all right. What the hell happened?
-你以为我希望这样？ -随便啦
- You think I wanted it this way? - Whatever,
我要挂电话了 我的律师随时会到
Gotta go. My lawyer's gonna be here any minute.
等等，听着
No, no. Listen, listen.
我要你告诉凯西 把责任都推给我
Now, look, I want you to tell Kacee to put it all on me, all right?
她因为害怕，不知该怎么做 知道吗？全部都怪我
And she didn't know what to do. She was scared. Okay? All that.
我已经这么跟她说过了
Yeah, I already told her to do that.
我来说话
I'll do the talking.
-欧文卡维奇？ -就是我
- Owen Kravecki? - That's me. Hey.
这两位是班和菲尔
Hey. Ben and Phil.
我们走吧，免得被老婆 发现我们偷跑去钓鱼
Let's go, before our wives figure out this is a fishing trip.
-你们的钓具呢？好 -放在北方当地
- Where's your gear? - I keep it up north. Okay?
要飞多久？
How long is the flight?
一小时四十分
An hour, 40.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
（新墨西哥州，阿布奎基）
很高兴你醒了
Glad you're awake.
你被击中锁骨和旋转肌之间
Collarbone and rotator cuff.
伤口再往右六寸 你就死定了
Six inches to the right, and you're dead.
对，他刚醒来
Yeah, he just woke up.
曼宏先生
Mr, Mahone,
我是比尔金，你真幸运
Bill Kim. You're a lucky man.
-是吗？ -凯勒曼完成了你没做到的
- Am I? - Kellerman finished the job you couldn't,
不过可惜他还活着
But he, unfortunately, is still out there...
他是未了之事
...and he's a loose end.
你得完成未完成的任务
Finish what you were supposed to take care of.
有什么好笑的？
Something funny?
凯勒曼不光 只是个未了之事
Kellerman's more of a loose end than you realize.
他开枪杀我
He shot me.
你想要背叛的人 先背叛了你
The guy you wanted to double-cross screwed you first,
斯科菲尔德和柏劳呢？
scofield and Burrows?
八成还活着
Are probably alive...
和凯勒曼一起逃亡
...and on the run with Kellerman.
祝你愉快，小金
Have a good day, Kimmy.
凯勒曼的档案已经删除
We neutered Kellerman.
世界上已经没有这个人了
He doesn't even officially exist anymore.
他知道所有的真相
He knows everything.
（蒙大拿州，布拉克富特）
（新闻快报）
Reports have been coming in from New Mexico officials,,,
新墨西哥州官方已宣布
逃犯迈克斯科菲尔德和林克柏劳
,,, that escaped convicts Michael Scofield and Lincoln Burrows,,,
已找到办法自行脱困
,,, have somehow managed to extricate themselves,,,
从移送他们回芝加哥的 囚车中逃出
,,, from a transport van that was bringing them back to the chicago area,
根据初期的资料来看 逃犯有K
According to this early information, the convicts were,,,,
你们真是厉害
You're great.
说真的，太厉害了
Top-notch. I swear to God.
别太激动 史泰门先生
Don't get yourself worked up, Mr. Steadman.
我现在早该恢复 正常的生活了
I was supposed to have my life back by now.
打高尔夫球K
Playing golf...
看电影K
...going to movies...
看朋友，但因为你们 连一个建筑师K
...seeing people. But because you guys can't get a handle...
和一个小混混都搞不定K
...on an engineer and a petty crook...
我已经当笼中鸟三年多了
...I've been a ship in a bottle for over three years.
你在这里很安全
You're perfectly safe here.
但愿如此
I wish.
我刚和金谈过
I just spoke to Kim.
他要你完成任务
He wants you to finish the job.
是吗？
Yeah?
不可能的事
That's not gonna happen.
这不是请求
This isn't a request.
也没有协商的余地
And this isn't a negotiation.
金和凯勒曼 要整天自相残杀我不管
Kim and Kellerman can try to kill each other all day long.
但我不干了
But I'm out.
你一定是忘了 我们有多熟悉内情
You must've forgotten how discreet we've been with what we know.
要公开席尔斯的事 随便你，我也会说
Go tell about shales. In fact, I will.
我杀了一个 凌虐、强暴女子的凶手
I killed a predator, a man who tortured and raped women...
把尸体埋在我家后院 我不怕坐牢
...and I buried him in my back yard. I'll do the time.
我不在乎了，我要退出
I don't care anymore. I'm out.
这么说够清楚了吗？
Is that clear enough for you?
我的朋友
My man.
真好吃
That's delicious.
等等，等等
Whoa, hold up there. Hold, hold up.
有个问题
We got a problem.
只有一块巧克力蛋糕
That's one brownie.
我们有五个人
There's five of my boys.
了解你害我多尴尬吗？
You see the position you put me in?
他们只能饿肚子站一旁 看着我享用美食
They gotta stand with their stomachs growling while I savor this delicious treat.
你害我变成一个浑蛋
That makes me look like a real ass.
你是故意害我当浑蛋的吗？
Are you trying to make me look like an ass?
你说的条件是 我给你一份甜点
You said the deal was I was supposed to bring you one dessert.
对，这个嘛K
Yeah. Well.
我是个反覆无常的小人
I'm a fickle bitch.
现在我每一餐K
Now, it's five desserts...
都要五份甜点
...every meal.
如果你拿不出来
Now, if you can't come up with that...
还有其他办法可以让我开心
...there are other ways to making me happy.
我身上还有其他糖果 可以给你
Well, I got some other candy on me, if you want some of that.
拿出来啊 你真厉害，你们要糖果吗？
Well, break it out, bitch. It's all good. You all want some candy?
狱警来了
Guard's coming.
我没记错的话 那天我也有去游乐园
If memory serves, I was at storytime Village that day too.
照片上都没有我？
And I'm not in any of these pictures?
我记得我真的有去
Could've sworn I was.
我只是逗逗你，宝贝
I'm just teasing, baby.
每个用火烧掉 情人照片的女人
Every woman has burned the photographs of her paramour...
之后都会发现她的爱火 烧得比之前更浓烈
...only to later realize her love burns even hotter than the flames she used.
拜托你！
Please.
泰迪
Teddy.
泰迪叔叔
Uncle Teddy.
我的小女孩好吗？
How's my girl been?
很好
Good.
你的成绩还是名列前茅吗？
You still getting more A's than an aardvark?
-对，我很想你 -我也是，小宝贝
- Yeah. I missed you. - Oh, same here, shortcake.
我染头发了
Yes, I painted my hair.
瞧瞧你，柴克
Look at you, Zack.
你已经长大成人了
You are a boy no more.
我很快就得借你刮胡刀了
I'm gonna have to lend you my razor soon enough.
你怎么来了？ 妈说你在钻油井工作
What are you doing here? Mom said you got a job on an oil rig.
对，就在海正中央
That's right. Right out in the middle of the ocean.
可是那些大机器很危险
But those metallic beasts are dangerous.
所以我受伤了
Got myself injured.
不要怕，甜心
Don't be, don't be frightened now, sugar.
我聘用的律师事务所K
The good lawyers at Dewey, Cheatem and Howe...
让我每失去一根手指 就赔偿一百万
...got me a million bones for every digit I lost.
五百万美金？
Five million dollars?
有了这些钱代表K
Which means with all that cash...
我想做什么都可以 而我只想要和你们K
...I can do anything I want now. And all I want to do...
花光我的钱，永远K
...is spend all my money and all my time...
在一起
...with you.
（蒙大拿州，卡特贝克）
邻近区域有什么？
What's the neighborhood like?
什么都没有 房子旁五十亩是空地
No neighborhood. The house sits on 50 acres.
我们要循原路出来吗？
We coming out the way we go in?
不，我们从后方的路走
No. There's a back road we'll take.
-有几个警卫？ -通常没人
- How many guards? - Usually none.
现在我不能确定
At this point, I really couldn't tell you.
我只要感觉有异
The second I feel this thing going bad...
就一枪杀了你
...you get a bullet in the head.
我想也是
I'd expect nothing less.
我每半小时会向你报告
I will inform you every half-hour.
了解
Understood.
欧文卡维奇 今早承租一架私人飞机
Private jet was chartered by owen Kravecki this morning.
-往哪里？ -蒙大拿
- Headed where? - Montana.
阻止飞机起飞
Stop it from taking off.
已经降落了，长官
It's already on the ground, sir.
通知史泰门
Call steadman.
如果是我姐姐 我要和她谈谈
If that's my sister, I would like to speak to her.
喂？
Yes?
马上办，长官
Right away, sir.
撤离
Evac.
史泰门先生，你有外套吗？ 我们得离开
Mr. Steadman, do you have a jacket? We need to leave.
离开？不要
Leave? What? No.
特务马上就会来 带你去避难所
Agents'll be arriving shortly to take you to a safe house.
我有什么危险吗？
What do I need to be kept safe from?
你有外套吗，先生？
Do you have a jacket, sir?
我不要走 我要找我姐姐谈谈
I don't wanna leave. I wanna talk to my sister.
我接到指示可以强行带你走
I've been authorized to use force if necessary.
你有什么东西想带走吗？
Now, is there anything you'd like to bring?
我的药物
My meds.
陪他去，车五分钟就到
Go with him. Car's here in five minutes.
我也不知道，史黛拉 她不肯出来
Well, I don't know, stella. She won't come out.
谁想要整天待在拖车里？ 你想吗？
Who wants to be up in the trailer all day, huh? Would you?
没错，我也不想
Exactly. Me, neither.
你想做派来吃吗？
You feel like making a pie or something?
樱桃派、柠檬派K
A little cherry, or lemon meringue, or...
爸爸
Daddy.
妈咪是不是和你一样 遇到麻烦了？
Is Mommy in trouble, like you?
甜心，过来
Sweetheart, come here.
过来
Come here.
听我说，好吗？
Now, you listen to me, okay?
妈咪没有做错事
Mommy did nothing wrong.
她只是在帮忙朋友
She's helping out a friend.
好吗？
Okay?
我去问问妈妈的情况，好吗？
Okay, let me go see how Mommy's doing, all right?
-我要和她说话 -不行，不行
- I wanna talk to her. - No, no, no.
你乖乖坐在这里等好吗？
You sit here, like a good little girl, okay?
不要这样
Don't give me that.
-喂 -有转机了
- Hello. - Things are looking up,
这才像话，说吧
That's what I wanted to hear. Kick it down to me.
她的律师很有办法 认为应该可以降低保释金
Her lawyer knows what he's doing. He thinks he can get the bail reduced.
很好，听着 等凯西出狱
Good, All right, well, listen, When Kacee gets out,,,
我要你帮我传话给她，好吗？
...I want you to deliver this message for me, okay?
告诉她K
Tell her...
我们可以消失
...that we can all get lost.
你要她弃保潜逃？
You want her to jump bail now?
你该庆幸你不在我面前 不然我会掐死你
Be glad you ain't in front of my face, I'd have my hands around your neck.
混小子，把话传给她就对了
Punk, just deliver the message.
之后你们怎么办？ 住在山洞里？
Okay. Then what you all gonna do? Go live in a cave?
-我有个计划 -好，说来听听
- I got a plan, all right? - Let's hear it.
我在伊拉克时
This guy back in my unit...
部队有个同胞
...when I was in Iraq.
他以前在阿拉斯加的 养鱼场工作
He used to go to Alaska, work at these fish hatcheries, man.
他们付现金
They pay you cash.
-不过问你的过去 -阿拉斯加？
- And nobody asks questions. - Alaska?
对，阿拉斯加 当地人不会多管闲事
Yeah, Alaska, man, They don't bother you up there, man,
我、凯西和蒂蒂 可以一家团聚，你懂吗？
You know, me, Kacee and Dede, we could be a family again. You feel me?
你真的不会放弃
Man, you don't quit.
我当然不会放弃
You're damned straight I don't quit.
可以告诉我要去哪里吗？
Do I get to know where I'm going?
到达后就会告知你一切资讯
You'll get all the information you need upon arrival.
-喂？ -带史泰门到第二个地点
- Yes? - Move steadman to Location Beta.
我们正派车要去接他
We're sending a car.
车已经来了，长官
It's already here, sir.
不可能
Couldn't be.
车子才刚出发
The car just left.
放下武器！
Weapons down.
快点！
Now.
放下
Down.
放下武器！
Put your weapons down.
别做傻事
Don't get stupid.
把武器放在地上，动作快！
Put your weapons down on the ground. Now.
戴伦斯，走开 上车去
Terrence, step away. Get in the car.
你这死人看起来真健康
You look pretty good for a dead man.
-上车！ -等等K
- Get in the car. - Wait, wait, wait.
-那是谁？ -凯勒曼，他抓走史泰门
- Who's there? - It's Kellerman. He's got steadman.
不要让他逃走
Do not let him escape.
杀死史泰门 杀死所有人，快点！
Kill steadman. Kill them all, now.
-保罗，拜托K不要杀我 -上车！快点！
- Paul, please. Don't... Don't kill me. - Get in. Get in the car.
我们走
Let's go.
麻醉后最难受的 副作用是呕吐
Vomiting. It's the worst side effect of anesthesia.
你应该不会再吐了
That should be the last of it.
-你认为我把食物都吐光了？ -对
- You figure I'm on empty by now? - Yeah.
潘
Pam.
亚历，卡麦隆受伤了
Alex, Cameron's been hurt.
-怎么了？ -是车子，肇事逃逸
- What happened? - It was a car. Hit and run.
他人在医院，腿有两处骨折
He's in the hospital. His leg is broken in two places.
我马上搭机到科罗拉多
I'll be on the next flight to Colorado.
-他正在动手术 -我马上到，你等我
- He's in surgery now, - I'll be right there. Just hold on.
他们不让我见他！ 他们打给我
They won't let me seem him. They called me.
我马上过来 可是他们不让我见他
I got right here and they won't let me see him.
潘，拜托，在我到之前先冷静点 帮我这个忙好吗？
Pam, please, just keep it together until I get there. Can you do that for me?
拜托，快来
Please. Please hurry.
曼宏先生 你不能搭飞机
Mr. Mahone, you cannot get on a plane.
你至少要住院一天观察
You need to stay at least another day for observation.
你中枪了
You've been shot.
曼宏先生，拜托
Mr. Mahone, please.
-我得见我儿子 -曼宏先生，我了解
- I've gotta go see my son. - Mr. Mahone, I understand.
拜托，至少先找医生谈谈吧？
Please. At least stay and talk to a doctor.
计程车！计程车！
Taxi. Taxi.
你儿子好吗？
How's your boy?
胫骨腓骨断裂很严重
Tib-fib fractures are bad.
但如果生长板受到影响 之后的问题就更多了
But if the growth plate's affected there's a whole host of problems.
-你做错事了 -不，是你错了
- You made a mistake. - No, you did.
你当我们是邮局 说不干就不干？
You think you can just quit like you work at a post office?
回到工作岗位上
Now, you're needed back in.
收拾你的烂摊子
Go clean up your mess.
科罗拉多州杜兰戈的街上 也许就不会再出意外了
Maybe there won't be another accident on the streets of Durango, Colorado.
懂了吗？
Understand?
封锁每条路 拦下每台车搜查
Every road shut down. Every car searched.
就算是到黄石公园观光的 一车修女也不能放过
I don't care if it's a group of nuns. Their camper gets turned inside out.
-以规模来说，每条路都查的话K -那是蒙大拿
- Logistically speaking, every road's gonna... - It's Montana.
不是曼哈顿
Not Manhattan.
-去办 -是，长官
- Get it done. - Yes, sir.
如果有照相机，可以拍下 他拿今天报纸的照片
If we get a camera, we can take a picture of him holding a newspaper.
照片放上网路 就可证明他还活着
If we put that online, that'll prove he's alive.
这只能证明我们找到 一个有点像总统弟弟的人
It'll prove that we found a guy that looks kind of like the president's brother.
-指纹、牙医纪录 -我们湮灭掉一切档案
- Fingerprints. Dental records. - We whitewashed him.
拔掉他的牙齿 烧掉他的指纹
We pulled his teeth, burned off his fingerprints.
DNA
DNA.
拿来比对我们杀死 放在他车上的游民
To compare against the homeless guy we killed and put in steadman's car.
但所有外在DNA样本都已摧毁
But we destroyed all exterior DNA samples...
所以也没有样本可供比对
...so that there'd be nothing to compare them to.
世界上一定有人 可以指认这个人
There's gotta be someone somewhere who can identify this man.
所以我们替他动手术
Which is why we did the surgery.
颧骨提高两公分 耳朵往下拉四分之一寸
Cheekbones raised two centimeters, ears lowered a quarter of an inch.
认识他的人 虽然可以认出他来
Not so much that someone wouldn't recognize him...
但足够让鉴识比对结果 判定照片上的人
...but enough that any forensic comparison of a photograph of that man...
只是长相类似的人
...would conclude that he is a look-alike.
一场骗局 相信我
A hoax. Trust me.
我们办事能力非常高超
We are very good at what we do.
拜托，放我走
Please, just let me go.
戴伦斯，你害这里每一个人 变成囚犯，包括你自己
Terrence, you made every man in this room a prisoner, including yourself.
-你该还我们自由了 -无论如何都不可能
- It's time to set us free. - Nothing you do will work.
-他们不会放过K -别再装无辜了，戴伦斯
- They will not let it... - Cut the victim act, Terrence.
当他借由生田公司 侵占纳税人的血汗钱时
He's happy to play along when he was lining his pockets...
他很乐意合作，之后K
...with taxpayer money funneled through EcoField. And then...
当事情快要暴露时K
...when the indictment is about to fall...
你跑去找谁帮忙，戴伦斯？
...who do you come running to for help, Terrence?
我们在这里住一、两天 直到他们以为我们已经走远了
We're gonna stay here for a day or two until they think we're thousand miles away.
然后我们就前往华盛顿特区
And then we're gonna make our way to D.C.
好吗？
Okay?
这是你的计划？带他去“公司” 和调查局的大本营？
So that's the plan? We take him to a city crawling with Company and Feds?
还有从里头与你父亲里应外合 依然当权的政府官员
And government agents still in power working from the inside with your father.
他们有办法让这浑蛋 在最有利的状况下说出实情
People who can get that pain in the ass to safely tell his story on the record.
直捣虎穴是吗？ 祈祷我们不会被吃掉
We just stroll right into the lion's den then, huh? Pray we don't get mauled.
我看他们不会来蒙大拿 所以我们要去找他们
I don't think they're gonna come to Montana, so we're gonna go to them.
不，放开她
No, Leave her alone,
-你想对她做什么？ -我只要跟她交往
- What do you want with her? - What I want is to date her,
抓她做什么K
What do you want,,,?
-我再去做点爆米花 -亲爱的
- I'll make you some more popcorn. - Honey.
如果我们还吃得下爆米花 我会很惊讶
If any of us could eat any more corn, I'd be amazed.
你懂吗，葛蕾西？
See what I did there, Gracey?
印地安语的玉米 和惊讶一字同音
Indian word for corn is "maize," and I just said, "amazed."
我听不懂，我被搞混了
I don't get it. I'm corn-fused.
你真是精明
You are smarter than a bee sting.
美国第二位女总统 就在这里K
The second female president of these United states, right here...
和我们一起看电视
...watching TV with us.
瞧我真笨拙
Look what I did.
-甜心，没关系 -不，我去拿抹布
- Honey, that's all right. - No, I'll get a rag.
不用，我可以K
No, I can...
我以为我们要重新开始
I thought we had wiped the slate clean.
求求你
Please.
我以为我们已经既往不咎
I thought we had put the past where it belonged.
的确，过去的事我不在乎了
We did. We did put the past where it belonged.
别骗我，女人
Do not lie to me, woman.
你向警方举发我K
After turn coating me to the authorities...
亏我们如此幸福 你重重敲碎我的心
...and everything we had. After breaking my heart into so many pieces...
让我永远无法恢复之后 你至少可以帮我个忙
...that I will never be able to find them all you can at least do me the favor...
不要当着我的面说谎！
...as to not stand there and lie to my face.
妈？
Mom?
柴克，回到沙发上坐好！
Zack, you get your ass back on that couch.
带葛蕾西逃出去！
Get Gracey. Go.
把枪给我！
Give that to me.
我已经给你们一次机会了
I gave you all a chance.
不要忘了
Remember that.
打开二十二号牢房
Open up 22.
二十二号牢房开了
Opening 22.
老兄，你真的疯了
Dude, you're crazy.
其他犯人也这么认为？
Is that what the other cons are saying?
-对 -很好
- Yeah. - Good.
你竟然敢惹班克斯 他不是你惹得起的对象
But you took it to Banks. I don't think you wanna be messing with him, man.
想找我麻烦的人我都敢惹
I'll mess with anybody tries to punk me out.
你知道我只是在测试你
Hey, you know, I've just been testing you.
好，测试结果出炉了
Yeah, well, the test results came back...
我要睡上铺
...and top bunk's mine now.
你有意见吗？
You got a problem with that?
-有事吗，史托特？ -布拉德，你这次死定了
- Hey, what's up, stolte? - You just screwed up, Brad. Big time.
不，我要让大家见识我的能耐 现在大家知道了
No. I had a message to send and that message got delivered.
你揍的人，班克斯
The guy you schlocked, Banks.
他和晚班狱警交情匪浅
He's got connections with the guards working nights.
有消息说今晚 班克斯会把你抓出牢房
Word is, Banks is gonna have you pulled out of your cell tonight.
-你没办法帮我吗？ -可以
- Well, can't you do nothing? - Yeah.
我可以警告你 所以我来了
I can warn you which is what I'm doing.
你不能找晚班的人谈谈吗？
Can't you talk to some of the guys working nights?
就是你分配他们 当晚班狱警的
They're working nights because you put them on nights.
你早该对他们好一点
You should've treated them better.
他们不可能帮你的，布拉德
They ain't gonna do you any favors.
我对你很好，不是吗？
Well, I treated you right, didn't I?
拜托，史托特
Come on, stolte.
你不能想想办法吗？拜托
Can't you do something? Please.
你的确对我很好
You did treat me right...
但现在我无能为力
...but there is nothing I can do now...
我只能警告你
...except warn you...
提高警觉
...watch your back.
我们可以用冰川国家公园 公园管理员走的防火道
We can use the roads that the rangers use in Glacier National Park.
晚上他们不会巡逻，我们进入 加拿大往东走，穿越纽约州
They don't patrol them at night. Get up into Canada, head east. Cut through New York.
-通过边境不成问题 -不会有人料到我们在那里
And the borders won't be a problem. No, nobody'll look for us there.
-你觉得很好笑吗，戴伦斯？ -不，不好笑
- This fun for you, Terrence? Really? - No, this isn't fun.
好笑的是当 卡洛琳和我聊到你
What was fun was when Caroline and I would talk about you...
还有你暗恋她的事
...and the schoolboy crush that you had on her.
他向她求过婚
He proposed to her.
你真以为你可以当第一丈夫？ 奴隶想当国王？
You actually thought that you would be the first husband? Serf who would be king?
卡洛琳
Caroline.
我们快笑死了K
We laughed so hard...
你眼睁睁看着他们 杀死哩诺卡
You stood and watched them kill Veronica.
-柏劳！ -你什么也没做！
- Burrows. - And you did nothing.
-柏劳 -都是你害死她的！
- Burrows. - She died because of you.
-林克 -闭嘴！
- Linc... - shut up.
柏劳，他死掉对我们没好处 他没有身份
Burrows, he has no value to us dead. He has no identity.
-杀了他，他只是具无名尸 -把枪放下
- Kill him, he's just a John Doe. - Put your gun down.
-他先放下 -林克，我们就差这么一点
- When he puts his down. - Linc, we're so close.
值得吗？害死那些人？ 毁了我的人生？
Was it worth it? Killing those people? Ruining my life?
-快搞定你哥 -闭嘴，别帮倒忙，别帮倒忙
- Get a handle on your brother. - Shut up. You're not helping.
林克，不要这么做
Linc, you don't want to do this.
相信我
Trust me.
这不是你要的结果
This isn't what you want.
你不会想这么做 懂吗？相信我
You don't want to do this, okay? Trust me.
死了这么多人
So many people dead.
他却能活下来
And he gets to live.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
法院拒绝保释
They denied bail.
-什么？ -法官不相信都是你在策划
- What? - The judge didn't buy that it was all you.
凯西要被正式起诉了
Kacee's going into the system now.
帮助逃犯的罪名 她的刑期可长了
Aiding an escaped con. She's looking at major time, man.
我要你告诉她的律师 你听好，告诉她的律师K
Now, I want you to tell her lawyer, all right, you listen to me. You tell her lawyer...
我爱你
I love you,
-告诉她的律师我会自首 -不行
...tell her lawyer I'll turn myself in, okay? - No,
凯西要你继续逃
Kacee says you need to run.
如果你被逮捕或是自首 蒂蒂会失去双亲
If you turn yourself in, Dede won't have either of you.
她会被送去寄养家庭
And they'll just throw her into foster care,
听着，我现在要挂电话了
Look, I'm gonna hang up this phone right now,,,
我怕我会说出令自己后悔的话
...because I might say something I'll regret.
拜托K
Yo...
你好好照顾蒂蒂就是了
You just take care of Dede.
柴克，你知道吗？
You know, Zack...
我的成长期间没有父亲陪伴
...my daddy wasn't really in the picture much when I was growing up.
所以我一直没有学会 木工的技巧
As a result, I never really learned the art of carpentry.
但我想耶稣是木工 他小时候也没有父亲教导他
But I figure Jesus was a carpenter, and his daddy wasn't around to teach him...
于是我自学
...so I taught myself.
一段时间后 我拿铁捶东敲西打很拿手
Over time, I got to be a pretty good swinger of the hammer.
好消息是K
Now, the good news is...
不像我父亲或万能的天神 我会永远K
...unlike my papa and the Great Almighty, I am here...
陪在你身旁
...for good.
千万不要质疑我的话
Don't make no mistake about it.
我们将是一家人
We will be a family...
就算同归于尽也无妨
...if it kills us.
好甜蜜
It's so sweet.
车子停在外面 准备动身吧
Car's out front. Let's move out.
他们不可能坐同一辆车的
These two will never make it in a car together.
-你得管好你哥哥 -你不了解他
- You keep your brother in check. - You don't know him.
那就把他的枪拿走 没时间瞎混了
Then get my gun from him. We don't have time for this.
你还认为操控权 在你手上，是吗？
You still think you're running this show, don't you?
到现在你还不承认吗？
You still think I'm not?
是，我要查 第十一台新闻部的电话
Yes, I'd like the number for Channel 11 News, please.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
这不在计划之中，挂掉
This is not the plan. Hang up.
好，接过去，我等
Yes, connect me. I'll hold.
你打给新闻台 他们就会报警
Scofield, you call the news, they call the cops.
好，接过去
Yes, put me through.
挂上电话
Hang up.
快点挂掉电话
Hang up the phone now.
快挂上电话！
Hang it up.
第十一台新闻部 有什么事能效劳吗？
Channel Eleven News, can I help you?
我是迈克斯科菲尔德
This is Michael scofield.
我在卡特贝克汽车旅馆 十一号房
I'm at the Cutback Motel, room 11.
我要自首
And I want to turn myself in.
小布拉德
Bradlee.
小小布拉德
典狱长回家了，贱人
Warden's gone home, bitch.
老鼠要出来玩了
The mice are gonna play.
小布拉德
Bradlee.
小小布拉德
小布拉德
Bradlee.
出事的话，如果你帮助我 我不会忘记的
If anything jumps off, you get my back. I won't forget it.
我看你干脆现在就忘记
Why don't you just forget it right now?
你在这间牢房里是老大
Here in this cell, you're top bunk. Out there...
出去外面，就得靠自己
...you're on your own.
小布拉德
Bradlee.
想揍我是吗？你们这些浑蛋！ 有种来啊！
You want a piece of me, you sons of bitches? Come and get me.
听到了没？
You hear me?
我不怕你们！
I ain't scared of you.
我什么都不怕！
I ain't scared of nothing.
小小布拉德
Bradlee.
开始祈祷吧
Start praying.
请说
Yes?
金先生
Mr. Kim.
我只想告诉你
I just wanted you to know...
我要回到工作岗位
...that I'm getting back to work.
很好
Good,
看来你收到我的讯息了
so I take it you got my message.
对
Oh, yeah.
清楚明白
Loud and clear.
别这么做，求求你K
Please don't do this. Please, come on, please.
抱歉，戴伦斯，太迟了 媒体已经过来了
I'm sorry, Terrence, it's too late. The press is already on their way.
你可以把枪收起来了
You can put the guns away now.
要是出事，我可不会帮你们
This goes wrong, you guys are on your own.
那让我回家好吗？ 拜托，让我回家
No, if I go back home. Okay? Let me, please. I'll go home.
戴伦斯，我们都回不了家了
You can't go home, Terrence. None of us can, okay?
你冷静点，保持理智
So just relax. Keep your head.
好吧K
Okay, okay, okay.
-戴伦斯！ -戴伦斯！戴伦斯！
- Terrence. - Terrence, Terrence.
我要离开！
I'm leaving.
戴伦斯，我们不能让你走
Terrence. We can't let you do that, Terrence.
我们只需要你的嘴 我现在可以打烂你的双膝
All we need is your mouth. I will shoot out your knees right now.
我从来没喜欢过你，保罗 杀你我不会迟疑
I never liked you, Paul. I won't hesitate to take your life.
好K
All right, just...
戴伦斯，听我说
Terrence, listen to me.
听我说
Just listen.
戴伦斯，就这一次 做正确的事
Terrence, for once in your life, do the right thing.
好吗？
All right?
有太多人受苦 就因为这件事，就因为你
So many people have suffered because of this, because of you.
但等媒体到达之后K
But when the press get here...
你可以说出真相
...you can tell the truth.
你可以终结这一切
You can end this.
我又能得到什么？ 耻辱？终生监禁？
What is in it for me? Disgrace? Life in prison?
你已经被监禁了，戴伦斯
You're already in prison, Terrence.
你要再害死多少人 好让你继续被关在
How many people have to die so you can stay in some cabin...
森林里的房子中？ 结束了
...in the woods? It's over.
好
Okay.
-对不起 -戴伦斯，不要！
- Sorry. - Terrence, no.
我们得走了
We have to go.
走去哪儿？ 史泰门在我们手上
Go where? We've got steadman.
不，我们什么都没有了
No, we have nothing.
我们只有一具无名尸
All we got is a John Doe.
迈克
Michael.
迈克，我们走
Michael, let's go.